Finding Aid for Joseph Ralston Hayden Papers
Bentley Historical Library
- Philippine collection
  - Education
    - Controversy over "single-double session,", 1932-1934 (Box 16)
      (16-19; 16-20)
    - Educational policy clippings, 1937-1940 (Box 16)
      (16-27; 16-28)
    - University of the Philippines
      - Minutes of the meetings of the regents, 1933-1935 (Box 17)
        (17-1, etc.-17-9)
      - University administration, papers about, 1934-1935 (Box 17)
        (17-10)
      - University faculty, papers about, 1934-1935 (Box 17)
        (17-11)
      - Jorge Bocobo, president of the university, papers about, 1935 (Box 17)
        (17-12)
      - Budget of the university, papers about, 1934-1935 (Box 17)
        (17-13)
      - Colleges of the university, papers about, 1934-1935 (Box 18)
        (18-1)
      - Reports of the university, 1921-1922; 1926; 1934; 1938 (Box 18)
        (18-3)
      - Library, 1931-1939 (Box 18)
        (18-4)
      - Miscellaneous papers, 1919-1935 (Box 18)
        (18-5; 18-6)
      - Clippings, 1936-1939 (Box 18)
        (18-7, etc.-18-10)
      - Philippine Women's University, clippings about, 1939 (Box 18)
        (18-11)
      - College of Agriculture, papers about, 1934-1935 (Box 18)
        (18-12)
    - Philippine universities and colleges, clippings about, 1931; 1937 (Box 18)
      (18-13)
    - Bureau of Education, report of, 1931 (Box 18)
      (18-14)
    - Miscellaneous papers about education, 1920s; 1930s (Box 18)
      (18-15; 18-17; 18-18; 18-22)
    - Miscellaneous clippings about education, 1922-1935 (Box 18)
      (18-16; 18-19; 18-20; 18-21)
    - Philippine students in the United States, papers about, 1923; 1934 (Box 18)
      (18-23)
    - Philippine Library and Museum, papers about, 1934-1935 (Box 18)
      (18-24)
    - Vocational education, clippings, 1937-1938 (Box 18)
      (18-25)
    - National Council on Education, clippings, 1938 (Box 18)
      (18-26)
    - Private schools (Box 19)
      - Papers about, 1930-1931 (Box 19)
        (19-1)
      - Clippings about, 1937-1939 (Box 19)
        (19-2)
      - Report about, 1935 (Box 19)
        (19-3)
    - "Teaching ban," clippings about, 1937 (Box 19)
      (19-4)
    - Public school system
      - Papers, 1935-1939 (Box 19)
        (19-5)
      - Clippings, 1937-1939 (Box 19)
        (19-7)
    - "School crisis," clippings about, 1936-1938 (Box 19)
      (19-6)
    - Religious education
      - Clippings, 1931; 1937-1938 (Box 19)
      - Report, 1938 (Box 19)
        (19-9)
    - Seminar papers written on the topic of education (Box 19)
      (19-10;19-11)
  - Foreign affairs
    - Japan
      - Economic investments of Japan in the Philippine Islands, report about, 1935 (Box 19)
        (19-12)
      - Threat of Japan to the Philippine Islands
        - Clippings about, 1939 (Box 19)
          (19-13)
        - Papers about, 1940-1941 (Box 19)
          (19-14)
    - Foreign relations
      - Papers about (Box 19)
        (19-15; 19-16; 19-18)
      - Clippings about (Box 19)
        (19-17)
    - Chinese in the Philippines, papers about, 1934-1935 (Box 19)
      (19-19)
    - Independence
      - Background of the independence movement (Box 19)
        (19-20)
      - Clippings about, 1926 (Box 19)
        (19-21)
      - Papers about, 1924-1933 (Box 19)
        (19-22)
      - Speech of Manual Roxas about, 1933 (Box 19)
        (19-23)
      - Clippings about, 1934-1935 (Box 19)
        (19-24; 19-25)
      - Clippings about, 1934-1935 (Box 20)
        (20-1, etc.-20-7)
      - Memorandum by Paul V. McNutt to the president relative to the Report of the Joint Preparatory Committee on Philippine Affairs (Box 20)
        (20-8)
      - Re-examination of Philippine independence, clippings, 1937-1939 (Box 20)
    - Relations with the United States
      - Bureau of Insular Affairs, papers about, 1937-1938 (Box 20)
        (20-10)
      - Resident Commissioner, clippings about, 1938 (Box 20)
        (20-11)
      - Bills in the U.S. Congress relating to the Philippines, papers about, 1935-1939 (Box 20)
        (20-12)
      - Action in the 76th Congress regarding the Philippines, papers about, 1939 (Box 20)
        (20-13)
      - William Cannon Rivers, papers about, 1935-1941 (Box 20)
        (20-14; 20-15)
      - Speech by J.R. Hayden entitled "The United States and Philippine Commonwealth" (Box 20)
        (20-16)
      - Report: "The Pacific Policy of the United States" prepared by the Institute of Pacific Relations, 1939 (Box 20)
        (20-17)
      - Speech by General Frank Parker: "The Philippine Archipelago and Guam in our Pacific Policy", 1940 (Box 20)
        (20-18)
      - Emigration of Filipinos from the United States, papers about, 1935-1936 (Box 20)
        (20-19)
      - Cocoa oil refund, clippings about, 1935-1940 (Box 20)
        (20-20; 20-21)
      - Daniel R. Williams and U.S. relations with the Philippines, papers about, 1928 (Box 20)
        (20-22)
    - World War II
      - Proposed post-war reconstruction program for the Philippines written by Tomas Confessor, paper about, 1944 (Box 21)
        (21-1)
      - Philippines in WWII, papers about, 1940s (Box 21)
        (21-2)
      - Provincial Governor of Free Lanao, report of, 1942-1944 (Box 21)
        (21-3)
      - Memorandum of Pascual Pacis about, 1945 (Box 21)
        (21-4)
      - Report compiled by the Office of Strategic Services, entitled "The Programs of Japan in the Philippines, 1944 (Box 21)
        (21-5; 21-6)
    - Seminar papers about foreign relations of the Philippines (Box 21)
      (21-7; 21-8; 21-9)
  - Historical and social topics
    - Aguinaldo and the "Philippine Revolution," papers about, 1899; undated (Box 21)
      (21-10)
    - "Aguinaldo and Philippine Freedom" (paper written by Carmen Aguinaldo Malencia (Box 21)
      (21-11)
    - Fiske Warren diary, 1901-1902 (Box 21)
      (21-12)
    - Cases of torture in the Philippines-Father Augustine case, 1902-1903 (Box 21)
      (Herbert Welsh file?)
      (21-12a)
    - Tagalog and the problem of a Philippine national language, papers about, 1935-1940 (Box 21)
      (21-13)
    - Jose Rizal poetry (translations) (Box 21)
      (21-14)
    - Miscellaneous topics, 1934-1935 (Box 21)
      (21-15, etc.-21-22)
    - Census, clippings about, 1938-1940 (Box 22)
      (22-1)
    - Press, papers about, 1926; 1932-1935 (Box 22)
      (22-2)
    - Press, messages to the, 1933-1935 (Box 22)
      (22-3)
    - Clubs and organizations, papers about, 1934-1935 (Box 22)
      (22-4; 22-5)
    - Invitations and programs to social events (Box 22)
      (22-6)
    - Sports, papers about, 1934-1935 (Box 22)
      (22-7)
    - Woman suffrage, clippings about, 1931-1937 (Box 22)
      (22-8)
  - Legislative/constitutional/judiciary
    - Commonwealth constitution (Box 22)
      - Papers about proposed constitution, 1935 (Box 22)
        (22-9)
      - Amendments to constitution, clippings about, 1936-1940 (Box 22)
        (22-10; 22-11; 22-12)
    - Presidential Emergency powers, clippings about, 1939 (Box 22)
      (22-13)
    - Government reorganization, clippings about, 1931-1932; 1935-1938 (Box 22)
      (22-14; 22-15; 22-16)
    - Judiciary
      - Clippings about, 1930-1940 (Box 22)
        (22-17; 22-18; and 22-22, etc.-22-25)
      - Papers about, 1934-1939 (Box 22)
        (22-19; 22-20; 22-21)
      - Miscellaneous judicial topics, papers about, 1935-1937 (Box 22)
        (22-26)
    - Legislature
      - Clippings about, 1922-1923; 1929-1935 (Box 23)
        (22-1, etc.-23-8; 23-10; 23-11)
      - Papers about, 1931-1932 (Box 23)
        (23-9)
      - Miscellaneous legislative topics, papers about (Box 23)
        (23-12)
      - Bills introduced and passed by the Philippine Legislature, 1934 (Box 23)
        (23-13; 23-14; 23-15)
      - Bills referred to, and commented on, by JRH, 1934 (Box 23)
        (23-16; 23-17; 23-18)
      - Department of public instruction bill, 1934 (Box 23)
        (23-19)
      - Health and immigration legislation (Box 23)
        (23-20)
      - Public welfare legislation (Box 23)
        (23-21)
    - Miscellaneous
      - Student paper entitled "The Constitutional Convention of the Philippine Commonwealth", 1937 (Box 23)
        (23-23)
      - Student paper entitled "Organization and procedure in the National Assembly of the Philippines", 1938 (Box 23)
        (23-24)
      - Legislative procedure of the National Assembly, papers about, 1931-1933 (Box 23)
        (23-25)
      - "Little Senate" bill, clippings about, 1933-1940 (Box 23)
        (23-26)
      - Applications for government positions, 1934-1936 (Box 23)
        (23-27, etc.-23-29)
    - National Assembly
      - Speech of President Manuel Quezon, 1941 (Box 24)
        (24-1)
      - Clippings about, 1934-1940 (Box 24)
        (24-2, etc.-24-8)
      - Vetoes of legislation by the Governor-General, 1933-1935 (Box 24)
        (24-9, etc.-24-11)
  - Political
    - Elections (Box 24)
      - Papers about, 1920s; 1938-1939 (Box 24)
        (24-12; 24-13; 24-17)
      - Clippings about, 1934-1938 (Box 24)
        (24-14; 24-15; 24-16)
      - Opinions on election laws (Box 24)
        (24-18)
      - Election Commission, clippings about, 1935-1939 (Box 24)
        (24-19)
      - Election Code, clippings about, 1938 (Box 24)
        (24-20)
    - Politics
      - Clippings about, 1931-1941 (Box 24)
        (24-21, etc.-24-24)
      - Papers about, 1930s (Box 24)
        (24-25)
    - Political Parties
      - Clippings about, 1934-1940 (Box 25)
        (25-1, etc.-25-8)
      - Democrata and Nationalista parties, papers about, 1922-1932 (Box 25)
        (25-9)
      - Colectivista-Nationalista coalition, clippings about, 1922-1923 (Box 25)
        (25-10)
      - Nationalista-Democrata Coalition, papers about, 1934-1935 (Box 25)
        (25-11)
      - Opposition to Manuel Quezon, clippings about, 1937-1939 (Box 25)
        (25-12; 25-13)
      - Aguinaldo and the National Socialists, clippings about, 1935 (Box 25)
        (25-24)
      - Ang Bagong Katipunan, clippings about, 1931-1932 (Box 25)
        (25-15-25-16)
      - Communist Party
        - Papers about, 1930-1934 (Box 25)
          (25-17)
        - Clippings about, 1929-1932 (Box 25)
          (25-18)
      - Communists and Socialists, clippings about, 1935-1940 (Box 25)
        (25-19, etc.-25-21)
      - Socialist Party, clippings about, 1938 (Box 25)
        (25-22)
      - Sakdals [Microfilm copy available]
        - Papers about, 1934-1935 (Box 25)
          (25-23, etc.-25-26; and 25-29)
        - Clippings about, 1935-1937 (Box 25)
          (25-27; 25-28)
        - Clippings about, 1937-1940 (Box 26)
          (26-1, etc. 26-3)
      - Proposed abolition of political parties, clippings about, 1930-1932 (Box 26)
        (26-4)
    - Personalities
      - Biographies of Philippine politicians, 1923 (Box 26)
        (26-5)
      - Manuel Quezon
        - Clippings about, 1933-1940 (Box 26)
          (26-6; 26-7)
        - Papers about, 1920s; 1930s (Box 26)
          (26-8)
        - Papers about and photographs of, 1944 (Box 26)
          (26-9)
      - Speeches of Quezon, Osmena, and others, 1936-1937 (Box 26)
        (26-10)
      - Sergio Osmena
        - Clippings about, 1936-1940 (Box 26)
          (26-11)
        - Papers about, 1924; 1938 (Box 26)
          (26-12)
    - Seminar papers about Philippine politics, 1939; undated (Box 26)
      (26-13; 26-14)
  - Provincial
    - Local and municipal government (Box 26)
      - Clippings about, 1931-1932; 1936-1939 (Box 26)
        (26-15, etc.-26-17; and 26-27)
      - Clippings about, 1936-1940 (Box 27)
        (27-1, etc.-27-4)
      - Papers about, 1926; 1934-1935 (Box 26)
        (26-26; 26-28)
    - Manila
      - Clippings about, 1934-1940 (Box 26)
        (26-19, etc.-26-23)
      - Sanitation, papers about, 1935 (Box 26)
        (26-24)
    - Municipal Councils and Port Boards, resolutions of, 1935 (Box 26)
      (26-25)
    - Provincial government (Box 27)
      - Papers about, 1930s (Box 27)
        (27-5)
      - Biographies of provincial governors, 1931 (Box 27)
        (27-6)
      - Press releases relating to, 1935 (Box 27)
        (27-7)
    - Mountain Province
      - Diaries/letters of Mountain Province visit, 1923 (Box 27)
        (27-7a)
      - Reports about, 1929-1941 (scattered dates) (Box 27)
        (27-8; 27-9; 27-11)
      - Papers about, 1931; 1934 (Box 27)
        (27-10; 27-12, etc.-27-19)
      - Clippings about, 1935-1937 (Box 27)
        (27-20; 27-21; 27-22)
    - Agusan [Microfilm copy available]
      - Reports about, 1933-1935 (Box 27)
        (27-24; 27-25)
    - Batanes
      - Papers about, 1934-1935 (Box 27)
        (27-26)
    - Bakidnon [Microfilm copy available]
      - Papers about, 1934-1935 (Box 27)
        (27-27)
    - Cotabato [Microfilm copy available]
      - Reports about, 1926; 1934-1935 (Box 27)
        (27-28; 27-31; 27-32)
      - Papers about, 1933-1935 (Box 27)
        (27-29; 27-30; 27-33)
    - Davao [Microfilm copy available] (Box 28)
      - Memoranda of J.C. Early about, 1930 (Box 28)
        (28-1)
      - Japanese in Davao
        - Report relating to, 1926 (Box 28)
          (28-2)
        - Japanese interests in, 1934-1935 (Box 28)
          (28-4)
      - Papers about, 1931 (Box 28)
        (28-3)
      - Reports of the Provincial Governor, 1935 (Box 28)
        (28-5)
    - Lanao
      (Microfilm copy available)
      - Reports of the Provincial Governor, 1932-1937 (Box 28)
        (28-6; 28-7; 28-8)
      - Report relating to the Moro problem, 1933 (Box 28)
        (28-9)
      - Letter from J.J. Heffington about, 1930 (Box 28)
        (28-10)
      - Papers about, 1933-1935 (Box 28)
        (28-11; 28-12; 28-13)
      - Clippings about, 1931-1936 (Box 28)
        (28-14, etc.-28-17)
      - Reports about, 1933; 1935 (Box 28)
        (28-18)
    - Zamboango [Microfilm copy available]
      - Reports of the Provincial Governor, 1934-1935 (Box 28)
        (28-19)
      - Reports about, 1931 (Box 28)
        (28-20)
      - Papers about, 1934-1935 (Box 28)
        (28-21)
    - Bureau of Non-Christian Tribes
      - Reports of the Director, 1934-1935 (Box 28)
        (28-22)
      - Clippings about, 1931-1935 (Box 28)
        (28-23)
      - Papers about, 1934 (Box 28)
        (28-24)
      - Papers about non-Christian tribes, 1934-1935 (Box 28)
        (28-25)
    - Moros
      - Correspondence about, 1926 (Box 28)
        (28-26)
      - Constabulary reports about, 1920-1933 (Box 28)
        (28-27)
      - Reports about, 1929-1931 (Box 28)
        (28-8; 28-9)
      - Memorandum about, 1933 (Box 28)
        (28-30)
      - Papers about, 1933-1939 (Box 28)
        (28-31; 28-33)
      - Governmental reorganization, 1934 (Box 28)
        (28-32)
      - Clippings about, 1931-1935 (Box 28)
        (28-34)
      - Clippings about, 1936-1937; 1940 (Box 29)
        (29-1, etc.-29-4)
    - Mindanao and Sulu
      - Report about, 1930 (Box 29)
        (29-5)
      - Colonization of, 1934-1935 (Box 29)
        (29-6)
      - Development of
        - Papers about, 1930 (Box 29)
          (29-7)
        - Report about, 1934 (Box 29)
          (29-8)
      - Clippings about, 1936; 1939-1940 (Box 29)
        (29-9; 29-10)
      - Report of the Commissioner for Mindanao and Sulu, 1937 (Box 29)
        (29-11)
    - Mindanao
      - Clippings about, 1937 (Box 29)
        (29-12)
      - Settlement of Mindanao, papers about, 1939 (Box 29)
        (29-13)
    - Sulu
      - Report of the Provincial Governor, 1929; 1932; 1935-1937 (Box 29)
        (29-14; 29-15; 29-20)
      - Monthly reports of the Provincial Governor, 1934-1935 (Box 29)
        (29-16, etc.-29-19)
      - Government employment survey for Sulu, papers about, 1931-1934 (Box 29)
        (29-21; 29-22)
      - Public health, report on, 1934 (Box 29)
        (29-23)
      - Education, papers about, 1934-1935 (Box 29)
        (29-24)
      - Budget, papers about, 1934 (Box 29)
        (29-25)
      - Speech of J.R. Hayden entitled "The Government of Sulu Archipelago,", 1936 (Box 29)
        (29-26)
      - James Fugate, provincial governor
        - Correspondence of, 1910-1937 (Box 29)
          (29-27, etc.-29-31)
        - Petition relating to, 1935 (Box 29)
          (29-32)
      - Arthur Spiller
        - Papers relating to, 1934-1935 (Box 29)
          (29-33)
        - Papers relating to charges brought against him, 1933-1934 (Box 29)
          (29-34)
      - Report of Major Charles S. Livingston entitled "Constabulary Monograph of the Sulu Province", 1915 (Box 29)
        (29-35)
      - Alagar affairs on Sulu, clippings concerning, 1932 (Box 29)
        (29-36)
      - Amoks on Sulu, papers about, 1934 (Box 30)
        (30-1)
      - Moros on Sulu
        - Papers about, 1934-1935 (Box 30)
          (30-2, etc.-30-5)
      - Report, 1928 (Box 30)
        (30-6)
      - Memorandum, 1933 (Box 30)
        (30-7)
      - Papers concerning province of Sulu, 1934-1935 (Box 30)
        (30-8; 30-9)
      - Clippings concerning province of Sulu, 1934-1935 (Box 30)
        (30-11)
      - Seminar papers concerning the Moros (Box 30)
        (30-12)
  - Miscellaneous topics
    - Clippings, 1930-1935 (Box 30)
      (30-13, etc.-30-26)
    - Clippings, 1934-1941 (Box 31)
      (31-1, etc.-31-17)
    - Papers, 1930s (Box 31)
      (31-18, etc.-31-21)
    - Hayden and the Philippines
      - Clippings, 1930-1933 (Box 31)
        (31-23, etc.-31-25)
      - Clippings, 1934-1938 (Box 32)
        (32-1, etc.-32-19)
    - Speeches, 1925; 1932-1941 (Box 33)
      (33-1, etc.-33-16)
    - Articles by or about JRH, 1931-1936 (Box 33)
      (33-17)
    - JRH's trips to the Philippines, 1922; 1926 (Box 33)
      (33-19)
    - Printed material (Box 33)
      (33-20; 30-21)
    - Philippines in World War II
      - Papers (Box 33)
        (33-22)
      - Printed materials (Box 33)
        (33-23, etc.-33-28)
    - Philippine Island newspapers, 1920s (Box 34)
      (34-1)
    - Receipts, 1930s (Box 34)
      (34-2; 34-3)
    - Addresses and mailing list, 1930s (Box 34)
      (34-4)
    - Travel vouchers for JRH (Box 34)
      (34-5)
    - JRH inaugural address, 1933 (Box 34)
      (34-6)
    - Radio broadcast between JRH, Manuel Roxas, and Congressman Butler Hare, 1933 (Box 34)
      (34-7)
    - Protestant missions on the Philippines, papers about, 1939 (Box 34)
      (34-8)
    - Miscellaneous, 2 folders (Box 34)
      (34-9; 34-9a)
    - Appendices and foreword to book about the Philippines (Box 34)
      (34-10)
    - Clippings, 1938-1939 (Box 34)
      (34-11)
    - Exhibit material (Box 34)
      (34-12, etc. 34-14)
    - Scrapbook including articles by JRH on the Philippines, 1923-1924 (Box 34)
      (34-15)
    - Scrapbook 1923, 1931 including articles by JRH on the Philippines (Box 34)
      (34-16)
    - Scrapbook concerning JRH and the Philippines, January-March 1935 (Box 34)
      (34-17)
  - Visual Materials
    - Photographs
      - Agriculture and industry (Box 35)
        (35-1)
      - Architecture (Box 35)
        (35-2)
      - Art collection (Box 35)
        (35-3)
      - Campaign (Box 35)
        (35-4)
      - Family and early photos (Box 35)
        (35-5--35-6)
      - Friends and colleagues
        - Identified (Box 35)
          (35-7)
        - Unidentified (Box 35)
          (35-8)
      - Health services (Box 35)
        (35-9)
      - Landmarks and monuments (Box 35)
        (35-10)
      - Murphy, Frank (Box 35)
        (35-11)
      - Mindanao views (mainly from tour of 1934-1935) (Box 35)
        (35-11-a)
      - Miscellaneous (Box 35)
        (35-12)
      - Natives (Box 35)
        (35-13--35-14)
      - Natives (from "Mountain Province letters"), 1923 (Box 35)
        (35-15)
      - Negatives (Box 35)
        (35-16)
      - Official functions (Box 35)
        (35-17)
      - Parker volcano (Box 35)
        (35-17-a)
      - Portraits (Box 35)
        (35-18)
      - Schools (Box 35)
        (35-19)
      - Sulu gathering, J. R. Hayden at (Box 35)
        (35-19-a)
      - Taft, William H. (at Philippine function) (Box 35)
        (35-20)
      - Views (Box 35)
        (35-21)
    - Album
      - Views of the Philippines and activities of JRH and others from their tour of Mindanao and the Parker volcano in, 1934-1935 (Box 35)
        (prepared and presented by Mark Parker, July 11, 1935)
    - Motion Picture films
      (original 16mm films digitized in 2009)
      - Philippine film-Batanes Islands, undated; [851643-1]; (Hayden was a University of Michigan professor of political science, specialist in Philippine Island politics and government, vice governor of the Philippines in the 1930s. Undated (probably from the 1930s), films may not be in original sequence.)
        - Original:, 16mm film, b/w, pos, silent
          [Restricted]
        - Use Copy:, DVD (Box 5)
        - Streaming File: 851643-1
      - Philippine film-Mindanao, undated; [851643-2]; (Hayden was a University of Michigan professor of political science, specialist in Philippine Island politics and government, vice governor of the Philippines in the 1930s. Undated (probably from the 1930s), films may not be in original sequence.)
        - Original:, 16mm film, b/w, pos, silent, 30:41
        - Use Copy:, DVD (Box 5)
        - Streaming File: 851643-2
      - Philippine film-Manila, Central Luzon, Ilocos Coast, Mt. Province, undated; [851643-3]; (Hayden was a University of Michigan professor of political science, specialist in Philippine Island politics and government, vice governor of the Philippines in the 1930s. Undated (probably from the 1930s), films may not be in original sequence.)
        - Original:, 16mm film, b/w, pos, silent
        - Use Copy:, DVD (Box 5)
        - Streaming File: 851643-3
      - Philippine film-Sulu Archipelago and Manila, undated; [851643-4]; (Hayden was a University of Michigan professor of political science, specialist in Philippine Island politics and government, vice governor of the Philippines in the 1930s. Undated (probably from the 1930s), films may not be in original sequence.)
        - Original:, 16mm film, b/w, pos, silent, 27:08
        - Use Copy:, DVD (Box 5)
        - Streaming File: 851643-4
- University of Michigan
  The University of Michigan series consists of four feet of University of Michigan class notes and lectures (currently unprocessed).
  - Class materials: Notes, clippings, etc (Box 36)
  - Class materials: Notes, clippings, etc (Box 37)
    (continued)
  - Class materials: Notes, clippings, etc (Box 38)
  - Class materials: Notes, clippings, etc (Box 39)
- Michigan Naval Division
  The Michigan Naval Division records were accumulated by Hayden during his years of service with the Michigan Naval Division during World War I. This series is currently unprocessed.
  - Materials, 1917-1919 (Box 40)
- File maintained by Lloyd Millegan
  (1971 accession to the collection)
  Lloyd Millegan was Hayden's assistant with the Philippine Research and Information Section. In 1971, he donated to the library Hayden files in his possession. This accession is a rich source of information relating to Hayden's activities during World War II with the OSS and as a civilian adviser to General Douglas MacArthur.
  - Question of U.S. sovereignty over the Philippines during the Japanese occupation, papers about, 1942-1943 (Box 41)
    (41-1)
  - Political situation in the Philippines and impressions of Douglas MacArthur and Manuel Quezon, letter of JRH to Jesse Reeves (letter never sent), September 29-November 7, 1935 (Box 41)
    (41-2)
  - Sulu and North Borneo areas, report about written by Captain J.A. Hamner, Philippine Regional Section, Allied Intelligence Bureau, 1943-1944 (Box 41)
    (41-3)
  - Personal correspondence, 1940-1944 (Box 41)
    (41-4)